<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tomcat | Eddú Meléndez]]></title>
  <link href="http://eddumelendez.github.io/blog/categories/tomcat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://eddumelendez.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-02T23:07:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://eddumelendez.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eddú Meléndez]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudbees]]></title>
    <link href="http://eddumelendez.github.io/blog/2014/04/27/cloudbees/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-27T21:49:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://eddumelendez.github.io/blog/2014/04/27/cloudbees</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time ago, I was looking for subversion server. I could have used Google code, but I had a problem with that, it is a public repository. So, I found <strong>Cloudbees</strong> and meets my expectation.</p>

<h2>What is Paas?</h2>

<p>Nowadays, we should know about <em>Platform as a Service</em>. But, it doesn&rsquo;t matter if you don&rsquo;t know it. You can learn something new everyday. Briefly, PaaS is a environment on cloud based on products from the providers. So, Cloudbees is a <strong>PaaS</strong>. In this case, Cloudbees was built using Sonar, Jenkins, Subversion, Git, MySQL, Tomcat and many other tools.</p>

<h2>What can you find on Cloudbees?</h2>

<p>You can find several products such as I have mentioned before, besides JFrog, SendGrid, AppDynamics, New Relic, Mongo HQ.</p>

<p>I suggest to use it at university projects. Sometimes we need to application server, and using Cloudbees we can have source control management, database, application server, maven repository. It is a good place to start teaching about <em>Continuous Integration</em>, <em>Continuous Delivery</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> We have to consider that Cloudbees provide a limit space, if you want more space you have to buy.
Cloudbees, is a good service. And I hope you can use it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
